[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c777", "question": "What animal species are ninth in the twelve-year cycle of animals in the Chinese zodiac?", "answer": "Monkeys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7ce72877e98cb97778a42", "question": "Which place is dubbed as \"The Salad Bowl of the Philippines\"?", "answer": "Benguet", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab957c86faa38a764be516", "question": "How many cylinders did the first generation Dodge Viper have?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339156", "question": "Who said: \"We are more popular than Jesus\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a1a1c612f2a7826b9b8715", "question": "What milk is Pecorino cheese made from?", "answer": "Ewe's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d7", "question": "What professor of physics oversaw the design and assembly of the first atomic bomb?", "answer": "J. Robert Oppenheimer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339690", "question": "What is the name of King Arthur's sidekick in the 1975 movie \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\"?", "answer": "Patsy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e0", "question": "Which British sax player fronted the band \"Paraphernalia\"?", "answer": "Barbara Thompson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa3", "question": "What do the Plastics call their \"slam book\" in the 2004 movie \"Mean Girls\"?", "answer": "The Burn Book", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc106e469bb8041d07a06e", "question": "What do you call a spiritual ceremony in which there is a deliberate attempt to contact the spirit of a deceased person?", "answer": "Seance", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397bf", "question": "What does Marilyn Monroe say are a \"girl's best friend\" in Gentlemen Prefer Blondes?", "answer": "Diamonds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a682", "question": "Which states share a border with South Carolina?", "answer": "Georgia and North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b44d01dd7bf43be5e7be", "question": "Where is the U.S. vice president's official residence?", "answer": "United States Naval Observatory", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25a6bb63e5727cf5a4853", "question": "Which rapper had hits including \"Who Am I (What's My Name)?\" and \"Gin And Juice\"?", "answer": "Snoop Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937edb608d98002fdd633ca", "question": "Beethoven's third symphony is named what?", "answer": "The Eroica", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc5ee6de0eb824d4052f6", "question": "The river Liffey flows through the centre of which European city?", "answer": "Dublin, Ireland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af81", "question": "What was Paul Revere's profession?", "answer": "Silversmith", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b125", "question": "How were Teddy Roosevelt and Franklin Delano Roosevelt related?", "answer": "Fifth cousins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be62", "question": "What signature color of paint are John Deere tractors?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc10cec223966ae8f8864", "question": "In the 2007 Superbowl, a player used what piece of equipment to make a catch?", "answer": "Helmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008a83cf842fa4c4ba9691", "question": "Traffic lights were first used in London in which year?", "answer": "1868", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ffc", "question": "Excluding Rudolph, how many reindeer pull Santa's sleigh?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601600cffe83fe1f2a824c58", "question": "What was the biggest downfall of flash photography in the late 1800s?", "answer": "Flash powder explosion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febaf0d7e83c707845b20fa", "question": "What is the most venomous fish in the world?", "answer": "Reef stonefish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fee", "question": "Which famous artist designed the Chupa Chups logo in 1969?", "answer": "Salvador Dali", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3fbec73aa70ea0b70b03", "question": "For the film \"The Empire Strikes Back,\" where were scenes set on the ice planet Hoth actually filmed?", "answer": "The Battle of Hoth scenes were shot on Handangerjokulen Glacier near the village of Finse, Norway.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6d", "question": "Who directed the 1983 sequel to the movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Sylvester Stallone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfbe89dc5ec6cd98a8319", "question": "Who painted The Son of Man?", "answer": "Ren\u00e9 Magritte (The surrealist intended\u00a0the painting\u00a0of a man whose face is obscured by a hovering green apple as a self-portrait.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396dc", "question": "What alien comes from the planet Melmac?", "answer": "Alf", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d3", "question": "In which movie did Russell Crowe play Maximus Decimus Meridius?", "answer": "Gladiator", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73482eec85e375820b236", "question": "Who was the first president to pardon a turkey?", "answer": "Harry Truman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe938846bd93ce3a4e5f686", "question": "What aquatic biologist is widely credited with helping launch the environmental movement?", "answer": "Rachel Carson", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b6", "question": "What movie stars Marlon Brando as a boxer who stands up against a corrupt union?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0e44469bb8041d07a05d", "question": "What candy company bought the Friendly's Restaurant chain in 1979?", "answer": "Hershey's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eee", "question": "What happened to Barry Allen after lightning struck the chemicals in his lab?", "answer": "He turned into the Flash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ed", "question": "What Harry Potter character has the patronus of a hare/bunny?", "answer": "Luna Lovegood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4af", "question": "At what nation does Panama attach onto South America?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd56", "question": "The Peabody Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Radio and television", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3bc", "question": "What is the common name for butterfly larvae?", "answer": "Caterpillars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe4", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madame Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b535", "question": "How many pawns does each player have at the start of a chess game?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338baa", "question": "Which book begins with the words \"It was five o'clock on a winter's morning in Syria\"?", "answer": "Murder on the Orient Express", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b292", "question": "What piece of technology did IBM develop in 1973 that they nicknamed Winchester?", "answer": "A disk drive", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a872", "question": "What is the name of the mainland portion of the province originally called Newfoundland?", "answer": "Labrador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacf", "question": "What is the study of the Sun called?", "answer": "Heliology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec89cfec223966ae8f882a", "question": "In which 2000 movie did George Clooney play Captain Billy Tyne?", "answer": "\"A Perfect Storm\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a82", "question": "Nick Carraway was the narrating lead character in which classic novel?", "answer": "The Great Gatsby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4de7906d333868d34d716", "question": "What was the Great Western Schism?", "answer": "When more than one pope claimed authority over the Roman Catholic church.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c553", "question": "What is studied by nephrology?", "answer": "Kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20e", "question": "Who was assassinated by James Earl Ray?", "answer": "Martin Luther King, Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8a6fec223966ae8f8831", "question": "In the movie \"Polar Express\", there is one rule when it comes to hot chocolate. What is it?", "answer": "Don't let it cool", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f1", "question": "Salton Sea is located in which western US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a55f", "question": "Which state is located directly to the east of Washington D.C.?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff1", "question": "Under what name is Thomas Lanier Williams better known?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d9b02596a59cbdfbd3c9", "question": "What was the first crime Billy the Kid was arrested for?", "answer": "Stealing clothes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe000ae1cf6db9ac4808d15", "question": "Which country has the oldest airport in the world that's still in operation?", "answer": "USA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd2", "question": "How many \"herbs and spices\" does KFC claim to have in their \"secret recipe\"?", "answer": "11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c77cc5c24f0f7a362efd53e", "question": "What is element is Wolfram?", "answer": "Tungsten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911d", "question": "What year did E. M. Forster publish the novel \"Howards End\"?", "answer": "1910", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef59326ce05a3942286e02", "question": "In the film \"The Shawshank Redemption,\" Andy had four pin-ups of famous actresses.  Which one did he not hang on his cell wall?", "answer": "Jayne Mansfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c37dc815febcc896f9275", "question": "What is the fourth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Cancer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce5", "question": "What team lost the pennant in 1908 thanks to \"Merkle's boner\"?", "answer": "The New York Giants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19a", "question": "Which two TV series from the 1980s featured a character named Uncle Jesse?", "answer": "Full House and The Dukes of Hazzard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078261bd51d85e222ab657", "question": "What artist believed he was a reincarnation of his dead brother?", "answer": "When he was five, Dali's parents told him he was a reincarnation of his older brother, who died nine months before he was born.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59636ac3967692ea851899a0", "question": "Which two cross-border neighbouring cities jointly celebrate July 1 and July 4 holidays with the International Freedom Festival?", "answer": "Windsor and Detroit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6eb", "question": "What does an archer keep his arrows in?", "answer": "Quiver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601de9f76b1208747aa7e9d5", "question": "In the Chinese zodiac, with which of the five elements is the snake associated?", "answer": "Fire -- It points to aggression and dominance.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7704eeec85e375820b2f7", "question": "What republic claims to be the world's oldest surviving republic?", "answer": "San Marino", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c9", "question": "What instrument was played by jazz musician Jack Teagarden?", "answer": "The trombone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c926", "question": "Which Salford brewer gave his name to the S.I. unit of energy?", "answer": "James Prescott Joule", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2139131a458464a93c450", "question": "In 2012, students at MIT hacked the lighting system of an entire building to play which game?", "answer": "Tetris", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a679", "question": "Which US state's name is derived from the Choctaw Indian word for \"red man\"?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febaa3e7e83c707845b20dd", "question": "How many main layers make up the earth's atmosphere?", "answer": "5", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff5135dff04d658268c92d9", "question": "What was the primary purpose of French activity in North America from 1492 to 1700?", "answer": "They were interested primarily in developing positive relationships with Native Americans that would foster the\u00a0fur trade.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b1", "question": "In 1975, what re-opened after an 8 year closure?", "answer": "Suez Canal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904a40fcf93664eb10486c1", "question": "Despite being referred to as Francine throughout the \"Strangers in Paradise\" comic book series, what is this character\u2019s real first name?", "answer": "Helen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c737", "question": "What does a lepidopterist study or collect?", "answer": "Butterflies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c4", "question": "Who wrote the 1897 horror novel \"Dracula\"?", "answer": "Bram Stoker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a8", "question": "Which country were the 1948 Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a594", "question": "What is the smallest ocean?", "answer": "The Arctic Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f1", "question": "What harbor is overlooked by Victoria Peak?", "answer": "Hong Kong", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7e910b24f84e0b9f9ffc8", "question": "What year did Botswana gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1966", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339500", "question": "What movie portrays a world where no children have been born in 18 years?", "answer": "Children of Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a99", "question": "What word becomes shorter by adding two letters to it?", "answer": "Short/small", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8d52ec223966ae8f8851", "question": "Which actor voices Miles Morales in \"Into the Spider-Verse\"?", "answer": "Shameik Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7f", "question": "What country gave birth to margarine in 1869?", "answer": "France", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c4dafbde8045e48466a3", "question": "Which animal\u2019s name translates as \"river horse\" in Greek?", "answer": "Hippopotamus -- From the\u00a0ancient Greek\u00a0(\u1f31\u03c0\u03c0\u03bf\u03c0\u03cc\u03c4\u03b1\u03bc\u03bf\u03c2), hippos spend a lot of their daylight hours in rivers and lakes to keep cool.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff668a652a821ff76ae8b07", "question": "How many electors make up the Electoral College in the U.S.?", "answer": "538", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b8", "question": "What is the largest cat in the America's?", "answer": "Jaguar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339911", "question": "What blues legend sings with U2 on the song \"When Love Comes to Town\"?", "answer": "B.B. King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162ca3f01ec323f8491731", "question": "What is the second largest country in the world?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949e", "question": "Who wrote the novel the miniseries \"Shogun\" was based on?", "answer": "James Clavell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc82eec223966ae8f888f", "question": "Which professional sport in the United States commonly has multiple games on Christmas Day?", "answer": "NBA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65665ae7e414034b5aec8", "question": "Who was the first Greek physician to keep records of his patients?", "answer": "Hippocrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a265", "question": "Who established Paisley Park as his own record label?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd7", "question": "What ingredient provides the pearls in bubble tea?", "answer": "Tapioca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58bb3216e368446ca7bd6840", "question": "Which element has the lowest boiling point?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa416fc73aa70ea0b70b0f", "question": "Which Hawaiian island is entirely privately owned?", "answer": "Ni'ihau (The island was purched by wealthy Scottish plantation owners from King Kamehameha V in 1864 for $10,000 in gold.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab0f", "question": "Which peninsula is Greece located on?", "answer": "Balkan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea470cff048f679a45aba8", "question": "Based on Kepler's first law, the path of a planet is defined as what shape?", "answer": "Ellipse", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b37701dd7bf43be5e7b0", "question": "A kindle is a group of what animals?", "answer": "Kittens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133994a", "question": "Who played Spiderman's arch\u00ad-nemesis, Green Goblin, in the 2002 Spider- Man movie?", "answer": "Willem Dafoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b920", "question": "What do Noodlers catch with their bare hands?", "answer": "Catfish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3c1dc4f032c0db195b47a", "question": "What Elizabethan theatrical impresario kept a famous diary?", "answer": "Phillip Henslowe's\u00a0modern reputation rests on the survival of his diary.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb54b65ff7d326b622a90", "question": "In Shakespeare's play \"Titus Andronicus\", who is Titus' daughter?", "answer": "Lavinia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594a62742ebb971c1417fb8f", "question": "In which Olympic games did Nadia Com\u0103neci become the first gymnist to be awarded a perfect score of 10.0?", "answer": "1976 Olympic Games", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab0c94baab681b09292168", "question": "How many toes does a gorilla have?", "answer": "10", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a0", "question": "Who played the role of the principal in the 2007 movie \"Charlie Bartlett\"?", "answer": "Robert Downey Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5956425b803c1f1ebcc4a02c", "question": "Tim McGraw and Faith Hill won the Academy of Country Music\u2019s very first Vocal Event trophy in 1997 for what song?", "answer": "\"It\u2019s Your Love\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a5", "question": "What is the hobby of autograph collecting called?", "answer": "Philography", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5be57f955415ba52ed6f0aac", "question": "The Rijksmuseum is located in what European city?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ae", "question": "Along with Karl Marx, who penned \"The Communist Manifesto\" in 1848?", "answer": "Friedrich Engels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c24d", "question": "Do sea gulls drink sea water?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339105", "question": "What city saw the debut of the 1875 opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339054", "question": "What was the name of Sherlock Holmes' intelligent brother?", "answer": "Mycroft", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af25aa1b63e5727cf5a4855", "question": "Which song was featured in the 1991 film \"Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves\" and held the number one spot in the UK singles chart for 16 weeks?", "answer": "(Everything I Do) I Do It for You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66bd552a821ff76ae8b10", "question": "Which was the last state in the United States that declared Christmas a legal holiday?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69cf220565ad31a57c771", "question": "Who sang the national anthem at Obama's second inauguration in 2013?", "answer": "Beyonce", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3e3244f0f6af5b066647", "question": "In mathematics which prefix refers to 10 to the power of minus 21?", "answer": "Zepto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9bd", "question": "What does a herpetologist study?", "answer": "Reptiles and amphibians", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d34c2596a59cbdfbd39a", "question": "Which city was the first capital of the United States?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a2", "question": "In which city could you find Bondi beach?", "answer": "Sydney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe6", "question": "The US Midwest experienced a severe drought known as the Dust Bowl, during what decade?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339200", "question": "What is the name of the White Stripes' drummer?", "answer": "Meg White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2aa", "question": "What type of cancer did actor Humphrey Bogart die from?", "answer": "Esophageal cancer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ac", "question": "Ants belong to what family?", "answer": "Formicidae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062a6ec9d816e292245c18", "question": "What Jewish German-born American sculptor helped usher in the postminimal art movement in the 1960s?", "answer": "Eva Hesse (She is known for her pioneering work in materials such as latex, fiberglass, and plastics.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd1e4ec223966ae8f88c1", "question": "While filming \"Guardians of the Galaxy\", what did director James Gunn give out as rewards to his actors and crew?", "answer": "Play-Doh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b511", "question": "How many days were there in 2004?", "answer": "366", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5b666ce05a3942286e15", "question": "Which actress was the first American to win a Ca\u00e9sar, the French equivalent Oscar, in 2015?", "answer": "Kristen Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc29f6ce05a3942286f1b", "question": "In the Clint Eastwood film, \"The Dead Pool,\" who plays the roll of Johnny Squares?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b7", "question": "Which airship is featured on the cover of Led Zeppelin's debut album?", "answer": "Hindenburg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935e", "question": "What was Matt Dillon's horse on \"Gunsmoke\" named?", "answer": "Buck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b6992cbe762b54eb9be9426", "question": "What country has the calling code +20?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601219af63c99d48cd169afa", "question": "From which language did the word \"Ketchup\" come?", "answer": "Chinese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d66", "question": "What is the subtitle of J.R.R. Tolkien's \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "There and Back Again", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ee", "question": "In the UK, what is called a \"courgette\"?", "answer": "A zucchini", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59067e8fff9c0647b50a807c", "question": "Which artist received the most nominations for the 58th Annual Grammy Awards?", "answer": "Kendrick Lamar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69ba820565ad31a57c762", "question": "Where did the United States' time zones come from?", "answer": "A railroad industry plan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9f", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Billy Budd\"?", "answer": "Herman Melville", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63e", "question": "What bird can swim but cannot fly?", "answer": "The Penguin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e5", "question": "Barn, Burrowing, and Great Horned are species of what bird?", "answer": "Owl", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a41", "question": "What \"couple\" would be known as Fischbacher and Horn if they went by their last names?", "answer": "Siegfried & Roy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcff", "question": "What American company had a thirty-foot inflatable gorilla atop its Rhode Island offices for decades?", "answer": "Samsonite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7147a9e54d890926f6dd", "question": "The second highest mountain on land is K2.  What does the letter \"K\" stand for?", "answer": "Karakoram -- K2 is located in the Karakoram Mountain Range.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69f9120565ad31a57c78d", "question": "What sport\u2019s first non-military competition was hosted in Norway in 1868?", "answer": "Downhill skiing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e6", "question": "Who played the role of Bobby Donnell on the TV show \"The Practice\"?", "answer": "Dylan McDermott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b54", "question": "What figure in Greek mythology was tricked into holding the sky?", "answer": "Atlas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b106", "question": "What Christian denomination was begun by John Wesley in 1738?", "answer": "Methodist", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac34", "question": "What is the first word of the text of the US Constitution?", "answer": "We", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a53b", "question": "What US city is nicknamed the \"Motor City\"?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5e296ce05a3942286e30", "question": "Which horror movie\u2019s sequel has the tagline, \"They\u2019re back\"?", "answer": "\"Poltergeist\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d4a", "question": "In 1803 The Louvre was renamed to what?", "answer": "Mus\u00e9e Napol\u00e9on", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b23f", "question": "What royal subject married Rita Hayworth?", "answer": "Aly Khan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a977", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Rajya Sabha?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925c", "question": "What French detective features in the \"Pink Panther\" movies?", "answer": "Jacques Clouseau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c7a", "question": "Which duo created the Indiana Jones character?", "answer": "George Lucas and Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7e09ff048f679a45ac06", "question": "Ataxophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Disorder or untidiness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e6", "question": "What was the name of the 90's TV show starring Jamie Lee Curtis and comedian Richard Lewis?", "answer": "Anything But Love", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b47f", "question": "Despite being fought by European countries, what modern-day country did the Battle of the Plains of Abraham take place?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339857", "question": "At the start of \"Howl's Moving Castle\", what does Sophie work as?", "answer": "A hatter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6df", "question": "Who collaborated with Beno Gutenburg to devise a system of measuring the intensity of earthquakes?", "answer": "Charles Richter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ccf78d0b37b32637bdc44bb", "question": "What is the name of Marvin and Trina's son in the musical \"Falsettos\"?", "answer": "Jason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afa2", "question": "Which tax was introduced into Britain in 1973?", "answer": "VAT", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339982", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who was Barney's high school sweetheart?", "answer": "Chloe Talbot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fbf", "question": "Who wrote the short novel \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff5150eff04d658268c92e6", "question": "What is the name of the boarding device used by ancient Roman warships?", "answer": "The corvus was a boarding-bridge with a heavy spike designed to pierce the enemy ship's deck when it was lowered.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be12", "question": "When going directly to jail, a Monopoly player is commanded not to do what two things?", "answer": "Do not pass Go, Do not collect $200.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339268", "question": "What movie did Michael J. Fox learn to skateboard for?", "answer": "Back to the Future", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943d", "question": "What 2000 movie depicts the war on drugs in Ohio, California and Mexico?", "answer": "Traffic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c8", "question": "Cr\u00e8me de Menthe, Cr\u00e8me de Cacao and fresh cream are combined to make what drink?", "answer": "Grasshopper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae77", "question": "To what tribe did Chief Tecumseh belong?", "answer": "Shawnee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab1b2de4fda37788a9a1dbe", "question": "Who directed the 1962 film \"Lawrence of Arabia\"?", "answer": "David Lean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a8", "question": "Whose California grave marker reads \"1935 - 1998 And the Beat Goes On?\"", "answer": "Sonny Bono's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0c6", "question": "What was the Tuxedo named after?", "answer": "Tuxedo Park, New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac99", "question": "Which of the US Presidents was the first to be born in the 20th century?", "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd0", "question": "The goddess Athena was responsible for causing whose hair to turn into snakes?", "answer": "Medusa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0df", "question": "Which pasta has a wide-ringed shape?", "answer": "Calamarata", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339353", "question": "For how many years was the \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\" on air?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82a", "question": "How many instruments accompany someone singing \"a cappella\"?", "answer": "None", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2b", "question": "Who became an animated Disney megastar after replacing Oswald the Lucky Rabbit?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b0", "question": "What is the main flavoring ingredient in a typical gin recipe?", "answer": "Juniper berries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0da95fcbed638185eaa06", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s highest inhabited city?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede3c76ce05a3942286dd6", "question": "What is Gary Oldman's character's codename in the 2011 spy drama \"Tinker, Tailor, Soldier, Spy\"?", "answer": "Beggarman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a954861d1b4d384d5d677", "question": "What is pumpernickel?", "answer": "A type of German bread", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc85551abc30a8194e188ac", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Deep\"?", "answer": "Peter Benchley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b3d", "question": "Who painted \"The Haywain Triptych\"?", "answer": "Hieronymus Bosch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c3e97a9ebfabb9c85d8a965", "question": "Which popular beverage's name is German for \"storeroom\"?", "answer": "Lager", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c05", "question": "Whose first hit single was titled \"Stubborn Kind of Fellow\"?", "answer": "Marvin Gaye's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a418", "question": "The Appalachian Trail runs over 2,000 miles from Maine to what southern state?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd61", "question": "What kind of sausage would more authentically be called \"mortadella\" in its namesake city?", "answer": "Bologna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121a3a63c99d48cd169b01", "question": "In which state can you be the farthest from a McDonald\u2019s in the contiguous U.S.?", "answer": "Nevada -- A spot in the northwest Nevada is 135 miles from the nearest three McDonald's. They are equidistant from each other.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51f", "question": "Which body joint includes the patella?", "answer": "Knee", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe655d1ae7e414034b5aebb", "question": "A golden apple sparked which famous war?", "answer": "The Trojan War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade0", "question": "Which dynasty preceded the Han Dynasty ending its rule in 207 BC?", "answer": "Qin Dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede5806ce05a3942286dee", "question": "What is the last line in \"Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer\"?", "answer": "\"You'll go down in history.\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ea0608d98002fdd6339e", "question": "Which Stephen King novel is set at the \"Overlook Hotel\"?", "answer": "The Shining", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae21", "question": "What is the famous brewery founded in Dublin in 1759?", "answer": "Guinness", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9bab4364247bf200fb89b", "question": "Tribology is the study of what?", "answer": "Friction, lubrication and wear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25a", "question": "What is 400 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "CD", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b479", "question": "The Battle of the Plains of Abraham was fought outside of which North American city?", "answer": "Quebec City", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace3", "question": "Who was already the husband of Octavia Minor when he married Cleopatra?", "answer": "Mark Antony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990af62b72eedf883a8c706", "question": "Which US state is known as the \"Mother of Presidents and the Mother of Statesmen\"?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e97", "question": "What movie did the villain Noah Cross appear in?", "answer": "Chinatown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa9316ce05a3942286edd", "question": "What was the name of Good & Plenty's classic engineer mascot?", "answer": "Jerry Rice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae934a574a5ce6b56b8239", "question": "Who was the Greek equivalent of the Roman goddess Juventas?", "answer": "Hebe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b55", "question": "What former pro athlete played Matthew McConaughey's father in the 2006 movie \"Failure to Launch\"?", "answer": "Terry Bradshaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff5", "question": "What is biltong?", "answer": "Dried meat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338928", "question": "Which rock group charted \"Land of Confusion\" in 1986?", "answer": "Genesis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd44", "question": "Who donated the only sock displayed on its own in the Baseball Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Curt Schilling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cda", "question": "In the movie \"Spaceballs\", what magic power is taught by the sage Yogurt?", "answer": "The Schwartz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c41b", "question": "What is the common word for a weight suspended from a pivot that can move freely?", "answer": "A pendulum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbbb", "question": "On what date did the \"Dennis the Menace\" comic strip debut in newspapers?", "answer": "March 12, 1951", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d1ba2596a59cbdfbd386", "question": "What was the uniform number of baseball players Willie Mays and Hank Aaron?", "answer": "44", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd4", "question": "What Robert Louis Stevenson novel was originally published under the title \"The Sea-Cook\"?", "answer": "Treasure Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ecaec9e790ded87bb38fd90", "question": "In the 1984 film, \"Purple Rain\", who did The Kid tell to purify herself in the waters of Lake Minnetonka?", "answer": "Apollonia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8945ec223966ae8f8827", "question": "The tagline \"Justice has its price\" comes from which 1998 movie?", "answer": "\"A Civil Action\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339024", "question": "What year did the first \"Where's Waldo?\" illustrated book hit the shelves?", "answer": "1987", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d46c2596a59cbdfbd3a3", "question": "Which bone exists as five separate bones when you are an infant?", "answer": "Cranium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b58f", "question": "What Cuban products include Montecristo, Cohiba and Romeo y Julieta?", "answer": "Cigars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd661f6a5bfecdd737e0840", "question": "What country has hosted the most Olympics?", "answer": "USA", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16d", "question": "What's the international radio code word for the letter \"M\"?", "answer": "Mike", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbd4b5d00d154d7af00b8cd", "question": "Who released the song \"Gettin' Jiggy With It\"?", "answer": "Will Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922a", "question": "What Welsh songstress has performed the themes for three different Bond movies?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dd70e748bb36357acde1", "question": "In the movie \"National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation\", what does Aunt Bethany recite when asked to say grace?", "answer": "The Pledge of Allegiance", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c88ea0222f44c2d77a29c4a", "question": "Where was the International Monetary Fund founded in 1944?", "answer": "The Bretton Woods Conference", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bebf", "question": "Sepp Blatter and Jack Warner are former executives from which international sports organization?", "answer": "FIFA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ab", "question": "In which country would you find the Negev desert?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8dd", "question": "The Yellow River is what country's second longest?", "answer": "China's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339507", "question": "Who provides the voice for Abe Sapien in the 2004 movie \"Hellboy\"?", "answer": "David Hyde Pierce", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6003983057a0e35c43f8389a", "question": "What French painter is credited with inventing the genre of f\u00eates galantes?", "answer": "Antoine Watteau\u00a0-- f\u00eates galantes consists scenes of bucolic and idyllic charm, suffused with a theatrical air.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb08", "question": "What newspaper was founded in 1889 by Charles H. Dow and Edward Jones?", "answer": "Wall Street Journal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f4c", "question": "How many syllables are there in Japanese haiku?", "answer": "Seventeen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb8557e83c707845b2133", "question": "What is the national bird of the Bahamas?", "answer": "The flamingo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb671b5dad637d903c883b", "question": "If you order \"murgh\" from the menu at an Indian restaurant, what meat will you get?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e39306d333868d34d72d", "question": "Which city served as the capital of the Ottoman Empire?", "answer": "Constantinople", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339750", "question": "Who won an Oscar for her role in the movie \"Annie Hall\"?", "answer": "Diane Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9bd", "question": "Which country's days include Fire day, Water day and Wood day?", "answer": "Japan's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff2592731a458464a93c46a", "question": "In what year was the NERF football created?", "answer": "1972 by former Minnesota Vikings' kicker Fred Cox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891a", "question": "What Italian city was Michelangelo raised in?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75d", "question": "In the eye, what is the more common name for the condition also known as \"lens opacity\"?", "answer": "Cataract", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fffa92473838c5c8a417f41", "question": "What material is the most expensive substance on earth?", "answer": "Antimatter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cea", "question": "What singer took his stage name from a Dublin hearing aid billboard?", "answer": "Bono", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339288", "question": "In the movie \"The Hunger Games\", what is Thresh's weapon of choice?", "answer": "A Scimitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66dd0a5bfecdd737e08a7", "question": "What is the currency of Poland?", "answer": "Zloty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9de", "question": "Which continent is the natural habitat of the Ostrich?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06b", "question": "Which Major Leaguer pitcher totalled the most strikeouts during both the 1970's and 1980's?", "answer": "Nolan Ryan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c140", "question": "Which brand name gets its name from the Finnish for \"Wild Grass\"?", "answer": "Timotei", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8ce2994b094db915830a5", "question": "At what age did legendary English musician, Lemmy, die in 2015?", "answer": "70", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ce683f302c3cfae5c79b719", "question": "On the day George Washington was first inaugurated as President of the United States, how many United States were there?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b982", "question": "What does a chrome-dome have a shortage of?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae33", "question": "When did the War of 1812 actually begin?", "answer": "1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90d", "question": "Who lost part of his ear to the teeth of Mike Tyson in 1997?", "answer": "Evander Holyfield", "category": "general"}]